Jinbin Hu | Curriculum Vitae

Department of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Hong Kong SAR – China

☐ +86-15274826560 • ☑ jinbinhu@ust.hk

I am currently a Post-doctoral from Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong SAR, advised by Prof. Kai Chen. My current research centers on network transport protocols and load balancing for large-scale DCNs, RDMA networking, learning-based network systems, Privacy-preserving Computing, and programmable switching architectures*.

Education

O PostDoc, Dept. of CSE, HKUST
Computer Science and Engineering
Advisor: Prof. Kai Chen.

Hong Kong SAR 1.2022-

Ph. D., School of Computer Science and Engineering, Central South University Changsha, China

Computer Science and Technology

9.2016–12.2020

Advisor: Prof. Jiawei Huang.

M. S., School of Electronic and Information Engineering, Beijing Jiaotong Univer-Beijing, China sity

Microelectronics and Solid State Electronics

9.2008-1.2011

Advisor: Prof. Xiaoguang Li.

B. S., School of Electronic and Information Engineering, Beijing Jiaotong Univer- Beijing, China

Electronic Science and Technology 9.2004–7.2008

Experiences

Changsha University of Science & Technology

Lecturer

Changsha University of Science & Technology

12.2021–

Teaching and researching in School of Computer and Communication Engineering.

Hunan Mechanical & Electrical Polytechnic Changsha, China
Lecturer 12.2021–8.2014

Teaching and researching in School of Electrical Engineering.

National University of Defense Technology

FPGA Verification Engineer

Changsha, China
8.2013–8.2014

Responsible for FPGA verification of multi-core CPU in Microelectronics Institute.

Empyrean Technology Co., Ltd

O IC Software Test Engineer

1.2011–8.2013

Responsible for IC simulation software testing.

^{*}Last Updated Jan. 2022

Publications

1.	Adjusting Switching Granularity of Load Balancing for Heterogeneous Datacenter Traffic Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang*, Wenjun Lv, Weihe Li, Zhaoyi Li, Wenchao Jiang, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, 2021, 29(5): 2367-2384.	6.2021
2.	CAPS: Coding-based Adaptive Packet Spraying to Reduce Flow Completion Time in Data Center Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang*, Wenjun Lv, Yutao Zhou, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, 2019, 27(6): 2338-2353.	10.2019
3.	RPO: Receiver-driven Transport Protocol Using Opportunistic Transmission in Data Center Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Zhaoyi Li, Yijun Li, Wenchao Jiang, Kai Chen, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. IEEE ICNP, 2021.	11.2021
4.	AMRT: Anti-ECN Marking to Improve Utilization of Receiver-driven Transmission in Data Center Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Zhaoyi Li, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. ACM ICPP, 2020.	8.2020
5.	TLB: Traffic-aware Load Balancing with Adaptive Granularity in Data Center Networks Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Wenjun Lv, Weihe Li, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. ACM ICPP, 2019.	8.2019
6.	CAPS: Coding-based Adaptive Packet Spraying to Reduce Flow Completion Time in Data Center Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Wenjun Lv, Yutao Zhou, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. IEEE INFOCOM, 2018.	4.2018
7.	Coding-Based Distributed Congestion-Aware Packet Spraying to Avoid Reordering in Data Center Networks Jinbinh Hu, Chang Ruan, Lei Wang*, Osama Alfarraj, Amr Tolba. IEEE Access, 2021, 9: 35539-35548.	3.202
8.	Survey on traffic management in data center network: from link layer to application layer Weihe Li, Jingling Liu, Shiqi Wang, Tao Zhang, Shaojun Zou, Jinbin Hu*, Wanchun Jiang, Jiawei Huang. IEEE Access, 2021, 9: 38427-38456.	3.202.
9.	Motion Prediction Based TDMA Protocol in VANETs Jinbin Hu, Wenjun Lyu, Shaohua Zhong and Jiawei Huang*. Electronics, 2020, 9(11), 1792.	3.202.
(*	stands for Corresponding author.)	

(* stands for *Corresponding author*.)

Research Project

o The National Natural Science Foundation of China

Study on Transport Control in Data Center Lossless Network Based on Priority-based Flow Control, 2022.1.1-2024.12.31